<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>index on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in index on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:43:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ipl-uv.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jesus Malo</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/jesus_malo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:43:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/jesus_malo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in understanding human vision from information theoretic principles. This statistical view has implications in experimental and computational neuroscience. See the ex-cathedra statement</description></item><item><title>Gustau Camps-Valls</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/gustau_camps_valls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/gustau_camps_valls/</guid><description>My research is related to statistical learning for modeling and understanding the Earth system.</description></item><item><title>Gherardo Varando</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/varando/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 04:37:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/varando/</guid><description>My research focus on probabilistic graphical models: Bayesian networks/DAG, Gaussian graphical models, staged event trees. Recently I am interested in structural recovery from spatio-temporal data, causal discovery and applications for the Earth sciences.</description></item><item><title>Post 3</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-3/</guid><description>Occaecat aliqua consequat laborum ut ex aute aliqua culpa quis irure esse magna dolore quis. Proident fugiat labore eu laboris officia Lorem enim. Ipsum occaecat cillum ut tempor id sint aliqua incididunt nisi incididunt reprehenderit. Voluptate ad minim sint est aute aliquip esse occaecat tempor officia qui sunt. Aute ex ipsum id ut in est velit est laborum incididunt. Aliqua qui id do esse sunt eiusmod id deserunt eu nostrud aute sit ipsum.</description></item><item><title>Post 2</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-2/</guid><description>Anim eiusmod irure incididunt sint cupidatat. Incididunt irure irure irure nisi ipsum do ut quis fugiat consectetur proident cupidatat incididunt cillum. Dolore voluptate occaecat qui mollit laborum ullamco et. Ipsum laboris officia anim laboris culpa eiusmod ex magna ex cupidatat anim ipsum aute. Mollit aliquip occaecat qui sunt velit ut cupidatat reprehenderit enim sunt laborum. Velit veniam in officia nulla adipisicing ut duis officia.
Exercitation voluptate irure in irure tempor mollit Lorem nostrud ad officia.</description></item><item><title>Post 1</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-1/</guid><description>Tempor proident minim aliquip reprehenderit dolor et ad anim Lorem duis sint eiusmod. Labore ut ea duis dolor. Incididunt consectetur proident qui occaecat incididunt do nisi Lorem. Tempor do laborum elit laboris excepteur eiusmod do. Eiusmod nisi excepteur ut amet pariatur adipisicing Lorem.
Occaecat nulla excepteur dolore excepteur duis eiusmod ullamco officia anim in voluptate ea occaecat officia. Cillum sint esse velit ea officia minim fugiat. Elit ea esse id aliquip pariatur cupidatat id duis minim incididunt ea ea.</description></item><item><title>Publications - books</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/books/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - conferences</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/conferences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/conferences/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - Journal</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/journals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/journals/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - talks</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/talks/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - theses</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/theses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/theses/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Research Earth Science</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/earth_science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/earth_science/</guid><description>Earth and climate sciences Motivation Machine learning has yielded many successful results and developments in remote sensing, geosciences and climate sciences. However, there are still strong limitations for the general adoption of machine learning algorithms for predicting and understanding the Earth and climate systems.
The current statistical treatment of biophysical parameters is strongly limited by the quantity and quality of EO data, as well as because of the abuse of standard off-the-shelf methods, which in general are not well-adapted to the particular EO data characteristics.</description></item><item><title>Research Machine Learning</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/machine_learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/machine_learning/</guid><description>Machine learning Motivation Machines may extract knowledge from measurements by analyzing the statistical properties of the acquired signals. The aim is to capture the structures in the experimental data. Our contributions to machine learning include algorithms for automatic classification (recognition) of objects, robust regression tools for multidimensional data, density estimation algorithms, and feature extraction and selection. We study the principled design of learning algorithms, specially neural networks and kernel methods. Methods are designed for general purposes but also specific to the application, most of them related to image processing, computer vision tasks and Earth science data analysis, but also non-structured data in social sciences.</description></item><item><title>Research Social Science</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/social_science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/social_science/</guid><description>AI for sustainability and social sciences Motivation The Earth is a highly complex, dynamic, and networked system where very different physical, chemical and biological processes interact, to form the world we know. The description of such a complex system needs of the integration of different disciplines such as Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics and other applied sciences, leading to what has been coined as Earth System Science (ESS). The analysis of the Earth system involves studying interacting processes occurring in several spheres (atmosphere, hydrosphere, cryosphere, geosphere, pedosphere, biosphere, and magnetosphere) as well as the anthroposphere where the Society acts.</description></item><item><title>Visual Brain</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_brain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_brain/</guid><description>Image and Video Processing:
Scene Statistics and Visual Neuroscience at work!
Controversies: don't use (1) the Mean Squared Error, nor (2) the image of Lena S&amp;oumlderberg. Here we only talk about the MSE issue.
MPEG-like video compression is based on predictive coding: i.e. motion compensation and residual quantization. Motion compensation consist of optical flow estimation (M module) and motion-based prediction (P module).Residuals (prediction errors) are analyzed in a different domain (T module) and quantized therein (Q module).</description></item><item><title>Visual Neuroscience</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_neuroscience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_neuroscience/</guid><description>Vision Science:
from Optics to Neuroscience and Statistical Learning
The PSF of this nice human eye can be measured in-vivo [Opth.Phys.Opt.97].
Linear V1 cells (see model here [Front.Neurosci.15]).
Linear response of MT cells
(and see the CODE for V1 and MT cells HERE) Vision is the ability to interpret the surrounding environment by analyzing the measurements drawn by imaging systems. This ability is particularly impressive in humans when compared to the current state of the art in computers .</description></item></channel></rss>