<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>index on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in index on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ipl-uv.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adrián Pérez-Suay</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/adrian_perez_suay/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/adrian_perez_suay/</guid><description>The topic of my thesis was Distance Metric Learning. Currently, I am working on kernel methods, dependence estimation and Machine Learning in general. I am interested on the applications of Machine Learning techniques to solve the Remote Sensing challenges.</description></item><item><title>Alice Re</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/alice_re/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/alice_re/</guid><description>I am a PhD student at Politecnico di Torino, Italy. My research focuses on preventive coastal flood assessment and mapping. During my research visit I will work on coastal flood susceptibility integrating remote sensing, GIS and ML.</description></item><item><title>Álvaro Moreno Martínez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/senior_research_scientists/alvaro_moreno/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/senior_research_scientists/alvaro_moreno/</guid><description>My research has been mainly focused on remote sensing applications in vegetation. I have been actively involved in the development of physical and statistical models and the implementation of operational methodologies for the study of vegetation cover through satellite imagery at different spatial/temporal scales.</description></item><item><title>Amparo Gil</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/amparo_gil/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/amparo_gil/</guid><description>In my MSc Thesis I developed cortical image representations that are simultaneously robust to neural noise and energy efficient.</description></item><item><title>Ana B. Ruescas</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/ana_ruescas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/ana_ruescas/</guid><description>I am a data scientist and project manager. As a remote sensing specialist I have experience in several application areas like ocean colour and thermal algorithm development and validation.</description></item><item><title>Anna Maria Mateo</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/anna_mateo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/anna_mateo/</guid><description>My current research focuses on developing machine learning algorithms for crop yield/production estimation using multi-scale remote sensing and climate data. Currently, I am working on anomaly detection in crop seasons and on the interpretability of the developed models.</description></item><item><title>Benyamin Kheradvar</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/benyamin_kheradvar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/benyamin_kheradvar/</guid><description>I am working on convolutional versions of linear + nonlinear models of visual neuroscience and using those in visual prosthesis and image quality metrics.</description></item><item><title>Borja Galán</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/borja_galan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/borja_galan/</guid><description>My research was tied to study feature representations that are sparse, interpretable and causal. At ISP I have been working in the Causal inference in the human-biosphere coupled system (SCALE) project funded by BBVA and the EC H2020 DeepCube project developing modules for interpretability and explainability in ML models.</description></item><item><title>César Luis Aybar</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/cesar_aybar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/cesar_aybar/</guid><description>I am working on the development of machine learning techniques for super-resolution in the ESA OpenSR project. My background is in Earth Observation.</description></item><item><title>Chen Ma</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/chen_ma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/chen_ma/</guid><description>PhD student in Harbin Institute of Technology, now visiting ISP. My research focuses on large foundation models and the processing of hyper/multi-spectral imagery.</description></item><item><title>Cristina Radin</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/cristina_radin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/cristina_radin/</guid><description>I am working on the development of statistical, physical and hybrid methods to study the regional effects of climate change in the oceans (MALOC project). I have a background in Earth observation data and machine learning methods.</description></item><item><title>Dan López</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/dan_lopez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/dan_lopez/</guid><description>The main goal of my research is to develop automatic algorithms for the detection of clouds from remote sensing images. I mainly focus on the inclusion of prior knowledge and (spatial, temporal, angular) constraints in machine learning classifiers.</description></item><item><title>Daniel Heestermans Svendsen</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/daniel_heestermans/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/daniel_heestermans/</guid><description>I am working on machine learning methods for remote sensing and earth observation data. My current focus is on kernel methods, and the incorporation of physical knowledge in statistical methods.</description></item><item><title>Deborah Bassotto</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/deborah_bassotto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/deborah_bassotto/</guid><description>I am doing my PhD on causal inference and complex system characterization of climate extremes.</description></item><item><title>Devis Tuia</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/devis_tuia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/devis_tuia/</guid><description>In my postdoc at the ISP group, I addressed a number of machine learning problems related to hyperspectral image processing including graph adaptation, active learning, and advanced kernel methods.</description></item><item><title>Diego Bueso</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/diego_bueso/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/diego_bueso/</guid><description>My research work is about machine learning and its application on remote sensing specifically in feature extraction and climate dynamics analysis. I am especially interested in soil moisture data analysis and climate teleconnections.</description></item><item><title>Emiliano Díaz</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/emiliano_diaz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/emiliano_diaz/</guid><description>My research interests include kernel methods, graphical models and causality, with the focus on Earth science applications.</description></item><item><title>Emma Izquierdo</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/emma_izquierdo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/emma_izquierdo/</guid><description>My PhD work included kernel-based nonlinear generalization of classical (linear) feature extraction techniques to improve classification results in remote sensing.</description></item><item><title>Enrique Portalés</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/enrique_portales/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/enrique_portales/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on novel deep learning architectures for cloud detection from remote sensing images, with special focus on domain adaptation and transfer learning strategies.</description></item><item><title>Eva Sevillano Marco</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/eva_sevillano/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/eva_sevillano/</guid><description>ISP Coordination &amp;amp; Project Manager. Ecologist by training. My research interests lie in Remote Sensing &amp;amp; GIS applications: multisensor support to forestry inventories, agriculture, land cover and change detection, geospatial data quality, Earth Observation products &amp;amp; services, etc. Collaborations with outstanding research groups and institutions, an asset. Onboard for new challenges!</description></item><item><title>Fatih Nar</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/fatih_nar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/fatih_nar/</guid><description>During my a year visit to IPL, I focused on processing optical images using kernel methods and variational methods, large scale anomaly change detection methods and digital terrain model (DTM) extraction. It was a joy to live in Valencia and life-time experience to work with productive and cheerful researchers in the IPL.</description></item><item><title>Fernando Iglesias</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/fernando_iglesias/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/fernando_iglesias/</guid><description>Research Associate in the German Aerospace Center (DLR), Ph.D. in Atmospheric Science from Lancaster University, UK. He works on combining causal discovery and deep learning methods to address systematic errors in climate models and improve climate projections.</description></item><item><title>Francesca Bovolo</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/francesca_bovolo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/francesca_bovolo/</guid><description>My work at the ISP group included the analysis of multi-temporal remote sensing image changes, and the definition of advanced one-class classifiers.</description></item><item><title>Francesco Martinuzzi</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/francesco_martinuzzi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/francesco_martinuzzi/</guid><description>PhD student at the Center for Scalable Data Analytics and Artificial Intelligence (ScaDS.AI) and the Remote Sensing Center for Earth system research (RSC4Earth), Leipzig University. My research interests lie in the exploration of nonlinear dynamics with machine learning, with a focus on applications to Earth sciences.</description></item><item><title>Gabriel Gómez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/gabriel_gomez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/gabriel_gomez/</guid><description>In my MSc work I applied accurate contrast perception models to improve Support Vector Regression in subjective domains for image coding.</description></item><item><title>Gherardo Varando</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/varando/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/varando/</guid><description>My research focus on probabilistic graphical models: Bayesian networks/DAG, Gaussian graphical models, staged event trees. Recently I am interested in structural recovery from spatio-temporal data, causal discovery and applications for the Earth sciences.</description></item><item><title>Gonzalo Mateo-García</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/gonzalo_garcia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/gonzalo_garcia/</guid><description>My background is in the field of applied machine learning. I am specially interested in applications to natural sciences like remote sensing and weather and energy forecasting. Currently I am working in transfer learning with convolutional neural networks applied to cloud and flood segmentation.</description></item><item><title>Gustau Camps-Valls</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/gustau_camps_valls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/gustau_camps_valls/</guid><description>My research is related to statistical learning for modeling and understanding the Earth system.</description></item><item><title>Helena Burriel</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/helena_burriel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/helena_burriel/</guid><description>At ISP I built virtual worlds of controlled spatial arrangement to study the effects of occlusion, perspective and view point in 2D shape statistics.</description></item><item><title>Homer Durand</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/homer_durand/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/homer_durand/</guid><description>I have a background in Applied mathematics and Statistics and, actually, my research focuses on Causal Representation Learning and applications for Earth Sciences. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in methods involving kernels and graphical models.</description></item><item><title>Inti Luna</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/inti_luna/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/inti_luna/</guid><description>I have a background in environmental sciences and experience working on remote sensing for vegetation studies (crops and forest monitoring). My research interests focus on monitoring and estimation of biophysical properties of vegetation (crop yield, crop water needs, forest biomass, and forest change detection) and soil moisture.</description></item><item><title>Ioannis Prapas</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/ioannis_prapas/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/ioannis_prapas/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a researcher at the Orion Lab, National Observatory of Athens and the University of Valencia. I am interested in Deep Learning for the Earth System sciences, aiming to improve fire prediction systems.</description></item><item><title>Irene Epifanio</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/irene_epifanio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/irene_epifanio/</guid><description>My PhD work (best-thesis award in Physics and Maths 2003) was focused on perceptual and statistical image representations for image coding and texture classification.</description></item><item><title>Irene Martin</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/irene_martin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/irene_martin/</guid><description>My research interests include machine learning and signal processing, especially deep neural networks and transfer learning. Currently I am working on applying physical constraints to ML models for better generalization, consistency and extrapolation capabilities.</description></item><item><title>Is this you?</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/is_this_you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/is_this_you/</guid><description>We are always looking for smart people! Send us your resume and ideas of collaboration!</description></item><item><title>Is this you?</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/is_this_you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/is_this_you/</guid><description>We are always looking for smart people! Send us your resume and ideas of collaboration!</description></item><item><title>Is this you?</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/is_this_you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/is_this_you/</guid><description>We are always happy to host smart people! Send us your resume and ideas of collaboration!</description></item><item><title>J. Emmanuel Johnson</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/emmanuel_johnson/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/emmanuel_johnson/</guid><description>My research at ISP involved feature learning and dependence estimation using kernel methods and multivariate Gaussianization with applications in Earth observation.</description></item><item><title>Javier Calpe-Maravilla</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/associate_professors/javier_calpe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/associate_professors/javier_calpe/</guid><description>My current research involves signal processing to develop new interactive man-machine interfaces and haptics, and real-time multispectral sensors and actuators. I&amp;rsquo;m also with Analog Devices Inc.</description></item><item><title>Javier Martínez Amaya</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/javier_amaya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/javier_amaya/</guid><description>I am working on the development of machine learning techniques to assess precursor conditions for extreme hurricane development (MALOPH project). My background is in remote sensing techniques, analysis and applications.</description></item><item><title>Jessenia Gonzalez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/jessenia_gonzalez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/jessenia_gonzalez/</guid><description>I am a PhD student at Leipzig University centered on understanding aerosol-cloud interactions directly from satellite observations using ML, bypassing the uncertainties inherent in traditional retrieval methods.</description></item><item><title>Jesús Malo</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/jesus_malo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/jesus_malo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in understanding human vision from information theoretic principles. This statistical view has implications in experimental and computational neuroscience. See the ex-cathedra statement</description></item><item><title>Jordi Cerdà</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jordi_cerda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jordi_cerda/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on the development and testing of the CauseMe website, a platform to benchmark causal discovery methods. My background is in physics and data science.</description></item><item><title>Jordi Cortes</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jordi_cortez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jordi_cortez/</guid><description>My research interests focus on kernel methods and the incorporation of physical knowledge in statistical methods to understand and improve Earth system modelling. My current research involves detection and attribution of climate change processes.</description></item><item><title>Jordi Muñoz-Marí</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/associate_professors/jordi_munoz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/associate_professors/jordi_munoz/</guid><description>At present I&amp;rsquo;m focused on kernel methods, support vector machines, semi-supervised and active learning. The main application field is on remote sensing data. I have recently worked with one-class classifiers applied to hyperspectral images.</description></item><item><title>Jorge García</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jorge_garcia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jorge_garcia/</guid><description>My research is about hyperspectral sensors and the estimation of water quality (WQ) parameters in optically complex waters to monitor coastal and inland biogeochemical dynamics, combining traditional bio-optical and radiative transfer models with novel machine learning techniques.</description></item><item><title>Jorge Vicent Servera</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/jorge_vicent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/jorge_vicent/</guid><description>My interests are related to atmospheric radiative transfer models, statistical regression emulation methods and image processing algorithms development and optimization. The application domains are remote sensing data analysis and hyperspectral images with special focus on atmospheric correction and scene/satellite simulation.</description></item><item><title>Jorge Vila Tomás</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jorge_vila/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jorge_vila/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on introducing human-like behaviours in deep learning models and measuring perceptual distances. I&amp;rsquo;m interested as well in generative models and reinforcement learning.</description></item><item><title>Jose Antonio Padrón</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/jose_padron/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/jose_padron/</guid><description>My PhD thesis was about developing a new family of anomaly change detection algorithms for remote sensing image processing and geoscience time series analysis.</description></item><item><title>José Enrique Adsuara</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/jose_adsuara/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/jose_adsuara/</guid><description>Currently, I am working on learning parameters of differential equations, HPC for linear solvers, and causality. I am interested in machine learning, especially statistical learning and deep neural networks.</description></item><item><title>José J. Esteve-Taboada</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/jose_esteve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/jose_esteve/</guid><description>I am developing computational models of the visual function based on functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging, psychophysics, and image statistics.</description></item><item><title>Jose Maria Tárraga</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jose_tarraga/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/jose_tarraga/</guid><description>My research interest is to study the impact of climate change on human mobility through machine-learning methods. At ISP I am working on the H2020 DeepCube Climate Induced Migrations use case.</description></item><item><title>Jose Rovira</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/jose_rovira/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/jose_rovira/</guid><description>During my MSc work I contributed to develop nonlinear local-to-global Independent Component Analysis.</description></item><item><title>Juan Gutiérrez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/juan_gutierrez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/juan_gutierrez/</guid><description>In my PhD I applied advanced contrast perception models as regularization functionals to solve inverse problems such as image restoration and motion estimation and studied their connection to image statistics.</description></item><item><title>Julia Amorós</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/julia_amoros/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/julia_amoros/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on image fusion, developing downscaling and pansharpening methods. The goal is to tackle multitemporal image fusion and change detection problems with improved resolution.</description></item><item><title>Kai-Hendrik Cohrs</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/kai_hendrik/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/kai_hendrik/</guid><description>My general research interest lies in Bayesian inference, deep learning and how to incorporate prior knowledge into machine learning models. Currently I am working on hybrid modeling in physics and how to overcome equifinality issues.</description></item><item><title>Koray Çiftçi</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/koray/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/koray/</guid><description>In my stay at IPL I addressed the problem of decoding the visual signals from simulated and real neural responses.</description></item><item><title>Laura Martínez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/laura_martinez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/laura_martinez/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with machine learning methods for crop yield estimation using climate and multi-sensor remote sensing data. My current research is now focused on the use of deep learning to upscale high resolution carbon fluxes.</description></item><item><title>Luca Capobianco</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/luca_capobianco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/luca_capobianco/</guid><description>My work at the ISP group included the development of target detection algorithms for remote sensing data analysis.</description></item><item><title>Luca Martino</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/luca_martino/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/luca_martino/</guid><description>My primary research interests lie in the area of Monte Carlo methods for Bayesian inference. My specialty is focused on the random number generation problem and computational methods for stochastic quadrature, such as rejection sampling, MCMC algorithms and importance sampling techniques.</description></item><item><title>Luis Gómez-Chova</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/luis_gomez_chova/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/full_professors/luis_gomez_chova/</guid><description>My interests are related to machine learning and signal and image processing. The application domains are remote sensing data analysis and hyperspectral images with special focus on cloud screening.</description></item><item><title>Manuel Campos-Taberner</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/manuel_taberner/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/manuel_taberner/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m with the UVERS group, doing my PhD thesis on biophysical parameter retrieval for crop monitoring, in particular in the FP7 ERMES project, and collaborating with ISP people on GP retrieval algorithms.</description></item><item><title>Mara Díez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/mara_diez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/mara_diez/</guid><description>While I was at ISP, I was conducting fMRI recordings of the visual brain using synthetic and natural images. I was director of the Optometry Clinic of the Universitat de Valencia, which has a range of experimental tools for vision research.</description></item><item><title>Marcelo Armengot</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/marcelo_armengot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/marcelo_armengot/</guid><description>During my stay at ISP I used with Kernel Ridge Regression for image denoising assuming smoothness in the spatial domain.</description></item><item><title>Maria Gonzalez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/maria_gonzalez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/maria_gonzalez/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on anomaly and extreme event detection from remote sensing images with attention networks and video prediction techniques.</description></item><item><title>Maria Piles</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/maria_piles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/maria_piles/</guid><description>My research interests include microwave remote sensing, estimation of soil moisture and vegetation biogeophysical parameters and development of multisensor techniques for enhanced retrievals with focus on agriculture, forestry, wildfire prediction, extreme detection, and climate studies.</description></item><item><title>Marina Martínez-García</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/marina_garcia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/marina_garcia/</guid><description>At IPL I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on computational visual neuroscience, modelling the processes that take place in the brain from the retinal images until we get information out of them.</description></item><item><title>Mattia Marconcini</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/mattia_marconcini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/mattia_marconcini/</guid><description>My work at the ISP group included the development of semi-supervised one-class classifiers for remote sensing data classification.</description></item><item><title>Mengxue Zhang</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/mengxue_zhang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/mengxue_zhang/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on hybrid machine learning for drought and heatwave detection.</description></item><item><title>Michele Ronco</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/michele_ronco/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/michele_ronco/</guid><description>My research focuses on understanding how deep neural networks work by using explainable AI (XAI) methods. In particular, I am following two complementary lines of investigation. The former consists in shortening the gap between physics-based and data-driven models by applying XAI in the context of Earth sciences and human-biosphere interaction problems. In addition, I work on the integration of prior knowledge into the learning process by either optimizing penalized losses or modifying the network architecture.</description></item><item><title>Miguel Ángel Fernández Torres</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/miguel_fernandez_torres/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/miguel_fernandez_torres/</guid><description>My research is related to the design of deep learning models and machine attention mechanisms to be deployed in anomaly and extreme event detection in the Earth sciences.</description></item><item><title>Moritz Link</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/moritz_link/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/moritz_link/</guid><description>My research focuses on modeling, characterizing and understanding microwave sensor data, with focus on soil moisture and vegetation optical depth. I&amp;rsquo;m actively involved in several ESA projects around the upcoming CIMR mission, and studying information-theoretic measures for observation-simulation intercomparison.</description></item><item><title>Nate Mankovich</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/nate_mankovich/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/nate_mankovich/</guid><description>I hold a PhD in Mathematics and am interested in applying my mathematical expertise towards utilizing manifold structures and causal relationships to develop dimensionality reduction algorithms for multimodal spatio-temporal datasets.</description></item><item><title>Óscar Pellicer</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/oscar_pellicer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/oscar_pellicer/</guid><description>During my PhD I employed machine learning for solving medical problems, focusing on medical image analysis for prostate cancer detection. I will now be applying the same techniques to satellite imaging, focusing on developing and explaining deep models for forecasting tasks.</description></item><item><title>Pablo Hernández Cámara</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/pablo_hernandez_camara/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/pablo_hernandez_camara/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on the inclusion of equivariant transformations, inspired by the human visual system, in the latest deep learning algorithms, with a focus on computer vision.</description></item><item><title>Paolo Pelucchi</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/paolo_pelucchi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/paolo_pelucchi/</guid><description>I am pursuing my PhD thesis in the iMIRACLI project on hybrid and interpretable machine learning for cloud-aerosol interaction problems.</description></item><item><title>Qiang Li</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/qiang_li/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/qiang_li/</guid><description>I worked on computational neuroscience via combined fMRI and image processing techniques to better understand the mechanism of the human vision system, which efficiently processes and extracts the information from the natural world.</description></item><item><title>Qiang Wang</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/qiang_wang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/qiang_wang/</guid><description>My background and expertise is on microwave remote sensing for soil moisture estimation, and agricultural applications, from estimating crop health and soil properties.</description></item><item><title>Raul Santos-Rodríguez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/raul_santos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/raul_santos/</guid><description>My work at the ISP group included the development of multiinformation and divergence measures using Gaussianization transforms.</description></item><item><title>Roberto Fernandez-Moran</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/roberto_fernandez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/roberto_fernandez/</guid><description>My current research focuses on cloud screening in multispectral imagery using machine learning techniques. Previously I was also involved in the algorithm improvement for the retrieval of soil moisture and vegetation parameters from microwave observations.</description></item><item><title>Sal Catsis</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/sal_catsis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/sal_catsis/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on causal discovery from observational data, and in particular to study climate-induced human migrations.</description></item><item><title>Sandra Jiménez</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/sandra_jimenez/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/sandra_jimenez/</guid><description>In my PhD years (best-MSc thesis award in Computer Science 2013) I analyzed the complexity of spatio-spectral signals for illumination invariant Bayesian reflectance estimation and hyperspectral image coding.</description></item><item><title>Shahine Bouabid</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/shahine_bouabid/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/visitors/shahine_bouabid/</guid><description>I am a final year PhD student in the Oxford Computational Statistics and Machine Learning group at the University of Oxford. I am interested in developing simple and interpretable statistical ML methodologies to address challenges that arise in climate science, in particular on climate model emulation using physically-informed models and statistical downscaling. I use mostly kernel methods and Gaussian processes.</description></item><item><title>Simon Donike</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/simon_donike/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/simon_donike/</guid><description>I am working on the development of machine learning techniques for super-resolution in the ESA OpenSR project. My background is in Earth Observation.</description></item><item><title>Soulivanh Thao</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/soulivanh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/soulivanh/</guid><description>My current research interests are related to statistical methods for the detection and the attribution of climate change and especially for the attribution of extreme weather events. Attribution methods usually rely on the analysis of observations and climate model experiments.</description></item><item><title>Tristan Williams</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/tristan_williams/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/phd_students/tristan_williams/</guid><description>I have a background in environmental sciences and remote sensing. I am pursuing a PhD within the XAIDA project where I will be using AI to attribute extreme climate impacts on European ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Valero Laparra</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/valero_laparra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/assistant_professors/valero_laparra/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working in image statistics and vision science. I have developed several methods for density estimation, measure independence, manifold learning and visual quality assessment.</description></item><item><title>Vassilis Sitokonstantinou</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/vassilis_sitokonstantinou/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/postdocs/vassilis_sitokonstantinou/</guid><description>I develop machine learning methods that incorporate causality and explainability, using Earth observations, climate data, and land use information. I analyze the impact of agricultural practices on ecosystem services and attribute crop failures to climate events. My goal is to provide data-driven insights for sustainable agriculture, towards expanding the global carbon sink while addressing global food demand.</description></item><item><title>Veronica Nieves - Distinguished Researcher</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/senior_research_scientists/veronica_nieves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/senior_research_scientists/veronica_nieves/</guid><description>My research at the interface between ocean sciences and climate informatics focuses on the development of the next generation of advanced algorithms to better understand our changing oceans and evaluate potential future climate risks. Research activities can be followed on I4OCEANS.</description></item><item><title>Vicent Talens</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/vicent_talens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/vicent_talens/</guid><description>In my MSc thesis I worked with a Kernel generalization of the SSIM image quality index well suited to be applied to hyperspectral images.</description></item><item><title>Yolanda Navarro</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/yolanda_navarro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:29:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/people/alumni/yolanda_navarro/</guid><description>In my MSc thesis I applied nonlinear models of chromatic contrast perception in wavelet domains to improve png2000.</description></item><item><title>Post 3</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-3/</guid><description>Occaecat aliqua consequat laborum ut ex aute aliqua culpa quis irure esse magna dolore quis. Proident fugiat labore eu laboris officia Lorem enim. Ipsum occaecat cillum ut tempor id sint aliqua incididunt nisi incididunt reprehenderit. Voluptate ad minim sint est aute aliquip esse occaecat tempor officia qui sunt. Aute ex ipsum id ut in est velit est laborum incididunt. Aliqua qui id do esse sunt eiusmod id deserunt eu nostrud aute sit ipsum.</description></item><item><title>Post 2</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-2/</guid><description>Anim eiusmod irure incididunt sint cupidatat. Incididunt irure irure irure nisi ipsum do ut quis fugiat consectetur proident cupidatat incididunt cillum. Dolore voluptate occaecat qui mollit laborum ullamco et. Ipsum laboris officia anim laboris culpa eiusmod ex magna ex cupidatat anim ipsum aute. Mollit aliquip occaecat qui sunt velit ut cupidatat reprehenderit enim sunt laborum. Velit veniam in officia nulla adipisicing ut duis officia.
Exercitation voluptate irure in irure tempor mollit Lorem nostrud ad officia.</description></item><item><title>Post 1</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/posts/post-1/</guid><description>Tempor proident minim aliquip reprehenderit dolor et ad anim Lorem duis sint eiusmod. Labore ut ea duis dolor. Incididunt consectetur proident qui occaecat incididunt do nisi Lorem. Tempor do laborum elit laboris excepteur eiusmod do. Eiusmod nisi excepteur ut amet pariatur adipisicing Lorem.
Occaecat nulla excepteur dolore excepteur duis eiusmod ullamco officia anim in voluptate ea occaecat officia. Cillum sint esse velit ea officia minim fugiat. Elit ea esse id aliquip pariatur cupidatat id duis minim incididunt ea ea.</description></item><item><title>Publications - books</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/books/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - conferences</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/conferences/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/conferences/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - Journal</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/journals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/journals/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - talks</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/talks/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications - theses</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/theses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/publications/theses/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Research Earth Science</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/earth_science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/earth_science/</guid><description>Earth and climate sciences Motivation Machine learning has yielded many successful results and developments in remote sensing, geosciences and climate sciences. However, there are still strong limitations for the general adoption of machine learning algorithms for predicting and understanding the Earth and climate systems.
The current statistical treatment of biophysical parameters is strongly limited by the quantity and quality of EO data, as well as because of the abuse of standard off-the-shelf methods, which in general are not well-adapted to the particular EO data characteristics.</description></item><item><title>Research Machine Learning</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/machine_learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/machine_learning/</guid><description>Machine learning Motivation Machines may extract knowledge from measurements by analyzing the statistical properties of the acquired signals. The aim is to capture the structures in the experimental data. Our contributions to machine learning include algorithms for automatic classification (recognition) of objects, robust regression tools for multidimensional data, density estimation algorithms, and feature extraction and selection. We study the principled design of learning algorithms, specially neural networks and kernel methods. Methods are designed for general purposes but also specific to the application, most of them related to image processing, computer vision tasks and Earth science data analysis, but also non-structured data in social sciences.</description></item><item><title>Research Social Science</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/social_science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/social_science/</guid><description>AI for sustainability and social sciences Motivation The Earth is a highly complex, dynamic, and networked system where very different physical, chemical and biological processes interact, to form the world we know. The description of such a complex system needs of the integration of different disciplines such as Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics and other applied sciences, leading to what has been coined as Earth System Science (ESS). The analysis of the Earth system involves studying interacting processes occurring in several spheres (atmosphere, hydrosphere, cryosphere, geosphere, pedosphere, biosphere, and magnetosphere) as well as the anthroposphere where the Society acts.</description></item><item><title>Visual Brain</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_brain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_brain/</guid><description>Image and Video Processing:
Scene Statistics and Visual Neuroscience at work!
Controversies: don't use (1) the Mean Squared Error, nor (2) the image of Lena S&amp;oumlderberg. Here we only talk about the MSE issue.
MPEG-like video compression is based on predictive coding: i.e. motion compensation and residual quantization. Motion compensation consist of optical flow estimation (M module) and motion-based prediction (P module).Residuals (prediction errors) are analyzed in a different domain (T module) and quantized therein (Q module).</description></item><item><title>Visual Neuroscience</title><link>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_neuroscience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ipl-uv.github.io/research/visual_neuroscience/</guid><description>Vision Science:
from Optics to Neuroscience and Statistical Learning
The PSF of this nice human eye can be measured in-vivo [Opth.Phys.Opt.97].
Linear V1 cells (see model here [Front.Neurosci.15]).
Linear response of MT cells
(and see the CODE for V1 and MT cells HERE) Vision is the ability to interpret the surrounding environment by analyzing the measurements drawn by imaging systems. This ability is particularly impressive in humans when compared to the current state of the art in computers .</description></item></channel></rss>