<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isp.uv.es/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gustau Camps-Valls, awarded with the Blaise Pascal Medal 2025 of the European Academy of Sciences</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2025/gustau_july/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2025/gustau_july/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls, UV professor and Image Processing Laboratory lead, won EurASc’s 2025 Blaise Pascal Medal for Earth and Environmental Sciences for hybrid AI, causal inference and remote-sensing methods that transform climate modelling. He’ll receive the award and deliver a keynote at CERN, Geneva, 17–18 December 2025, recognising his geoscience contributions.</description></item><item><title>Diseñan, mediante IA, sistemas de alerta temprana más efectivos para la toma de decisiones frente a los impactos del cambio climático</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2025/estudio_internacional/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2025/estudio_internacional/</guid><description>Tras revisar el uso de la Inteligencia Artificial (IA) para mejorar la comprensión de fenómenos climáticos extremos, un equipo internacional de investigación con destacada participación de la Universitat de València (UV) ha publicado un estudio que explora cómo, mediante modelos avanzados de IA, pueden diseñarse sistemas de alerta temprana más efectivos y adaptables tanto para la prevención de impactos ocasionados por el cambio climático como para la toma de decisiones.</description></item><item><title>Un estudio determina que la IA será ‘clave’ para mitigar los impactos del cambio climático</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2025/estudios_ia_impactos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2025/estudios_ia_impactos/</guid><description>El uso de la Inteligencia Artificial (IA) será “clave” para mitigar los impactos del cambio climático, como las “devastadoras inundaciones” de Valencia (este de España) el pasado octubre, según un estudio que un equipo internacional de investigación coliderado por la Universitat de Valencia acaba de publicar en ‘Nature Communications’.</description></item><item><title>Un estudio internacional reclama una alianza equilibrada entre la IA y las ciencias de la Tierra ante los retos ambientales</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2024/estudio_internacional/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2024/estudio_internacional/</guid><description>Un equipo de investigación internacional con participación de la Universitat de València ha publicado un artículo, en la revista Nature Geoscience, que reclama un enfoque más colaborativo y equilibrado entre la inteligencia artificial y las ciencias de la Tierra. El estudio defiende un nuevo campo de estudio –AIXES (Artificial Intelligence and Earth Sciences)– que mejorará ambas esferas y resultará beneficioso a la hora de abordar los retos de futuro ambientales.</description></item><item><title>La inteligencia artificial, una herramienta en la lucha contra el cambio climático: las predicciones serán más rápidas y precisas</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2024/herramienta_lucha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2024/herramienta_lucha/</guid><description>Un equipo científico internacional, liderado por la profesora Veronika Eyring, del Centro Aeroespacial Alemán (DLR) y la Universidad de Bremen, y en el que participa la Universitat de València, ha publicado un innovador enfoque que integra inteligencia artificial (IA) con modelos del sistema terrestre para mejorar la precisión y velocidad de las simulaciones climáticas. La propuesta, publicada en la revista en la revista Nature Geoscience, es fundamental para la toma de decisiones en mitigación y adaptación al cambio climático.</description></item><item><title>Expertos en IA y clima analizan en València la "revolución" tecnológica aplicada a la predicción meteorológica</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2024/expertos_ia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2024/expertos_ia/</guid><description>La Universitat de València (uv) concentra estos días a una treintena de especialistas en Inteligencia Artificial (IA) y Machine Learning aplicados a la predicción meteorológica, la emulación climática y la generación de modelos del sistema terrestre. Organizada por el Image Processing Laboratory (IPL), el workshop se produce bajo el paraguas de la red ELLIS y del proyecto asociado ELISE.</description></item><item><title>Conferencias sobre IA en Fundación Cañada Blanch</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/fundacion-canada-blanch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/fundacion-canada-blanch/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls, reconocido internacionalmente por sus contribuciones en Inteligencia Artificial, aprendizaje automático y su aplicación en las ciencias de la tierra y el clima, inicia un ciclo de conferencias sobre IA en la Fundación Cañada Blanch.</description></item><item><title>ELLIS Meeting in Valencia</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/ellis-meeting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/ellis-meeting/</guid><description>The UV and the ISP gathers in València (Spain) world-renowned experts in two interconnected fields: climate change and artificial intelligence. The meeting is organized by the ELLIS Program ‘Machine Learning for Earth and Climate Sciences’ and the ELISE project, which connect outstanding researchers in these fields across Europe. The discussions will focus on detecting, analyzing, and understanding extreme weather events, such as droughts, heat waves, floods, fires, and hurricanes, and applying artificial intelligence in this context.</description></item><item><title>ISP organiza reuniones sobre fenómenos meteorológicos extremos</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/isp-reuniones/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/isp-reuniones/</guid><description>El ISP organiza dos reuniones que reúnen expertos en fenómenos meteorológicos extremos y en la aplicación de algoritmos en València. Las reuniones estudian estrategias para la detección temprana, dentro de acciones en los proyectos europeos H2020 XAIDA y del programa de investigación en ELLIS &amp;ldquo;Machine Learning for Earth and Climate Science&amp;rdquo;, coordinados por Gustau Camps-Valls.</description></item><item><title>Finalists for ESA-EGU 2023</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/esa-egu-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/esa-egu-2023/</guid><description>The group led by Gustau Camps-Valls from the University of Valencia in Spain is finalist for the ESA-EGU 2023 team award, for their work on the development of novel Artificial Intelligence methods to analyse Earth observation data, with the goal of modelling and understanding the complex interactions between the various components of the Earth system.</description></item><item><title>AI4CS - GVA PROMETEO 2022-2025</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/ai4cs-prometeo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/ai4cs-prometeo/</guid><description>AI4CS - GVA PROMETEO 2022-2025 AI for complex systems: Brain, Earth, Climate, Society. We are hosting the first project meeting in person! The aim is to know each other better, find common points of interest and organize activities e.g. workshops, PhD students exchange, research designs, etc. Presentations by Marcelo Bertalmío from CSIC, Luca Martino from URJC, Sancho Salcedo from UAH, Adriano Camps from UPC, Luis Guanter from UPV, and Gustau Camps-Valls, followed by discussions about limitations on the standard model of vision science, imaging and AI, model and feature selection trade-offs, extreme event predictions and diverse AI-relevant Remote Sensing case studies.</description></item><item><title>AI for Earth and Sustainability Science</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/ai-for-earth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/ai-for-earth/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls, Markus Reichstein, Joachim Denzler y Maria Piles coordinan el ciclo &amp;ldquo;AI for Earth and Sustainability Science&amp;rdquo; dentro de las acciones AI for Good de la ITU.</description></item><item><title>La IA demuestra que el nivel socioeconómico condiciona las migraciones por catástrofes ambientales</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/nature-communications-ia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2023/nature-communications-ia/</guid><description>Un artículo del grupo de investigación Image and Signal Processing (ISP) de la Universitat de Valncia (UV), liderado por Gustau Camps-Valls y que ha utilizado la Inteligencia Artificial (IA) como herramienta, concluye que el nivel socioeconómico explica los movimientos poblacionales que se dan tras catástrofes generadas por fenómenos naturales extremos como inundaciones, vendavales y deslizamientos de tierra.</description></item><item><title>Cuatro científicos de la Universitat de València, en la élite mundial por las citas de sus artículos</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/highly-cited-researcher/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/highly-cited-researcher/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls is a Highly Cited Researcher in 2022 again!</description></item><item><title>Artículo sobre las limitaciones de la IA</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/ia-limitations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/ia-limitations/</guid><description>El prof. Camps-Valls publica un artículo advirtiendo de las limitaciones de la IA actual, y aboga por incorporar conocimiento del dominio y las leyes de la Física, realizar un mayor esfuerzo en la explicabilidad de los modelos, y en la inferencia causal.</description></item><item><title>Participation in ELISE project</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/elise-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/elise-project/</guid><description>The ISP participates in the ELISE project actively, and contributes to the ELISE vision for the next generation of AI for Europe. In particular, on ELISE’s Strategic Research Agenda and trends in AI!</description></item><item><title>AI4Science DeepExtremes Project Kicked-off</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/ai4science-deepextremes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/ai4science-deepextremes/</guid><description>ESA 2022-23 AI4Science DeepExtremes Project Kicked-off! Multi-Hazards, Compounds and Cascade events. We will rely on deep learning to deal with spatio-temporal data, techniques from computer vision for forecasting impacts, and the advanced regression methods for associating impacts on biosphere and society. Understanding what the DL models have learned are of importance here: explainable AI techniques and methods from modern Bayesian inference. Follow us on Twitter DeepExtremes LeipzigValenciaJenaHamburg.</description></item><item><title>Gustau Camps-Valls, nuevo miembro de la Academia Europea de Ciencias y de la Europea</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/nuevo-miembro-academia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2022/nuevo-miembro-academia/</guid><description>El prof. Camps-Valls es un nuevo miembro de la Academia Europea de las Ciencias, y de la Academia Europaea.</description></item><item><title>Horizon 2020 EU XAIDA Kick-off</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/horizon-2020-xaida/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/horizon-2020-xaida/</guid><description>Kick-off September! Horizon 2020 EU XAIDA Extreme Events: Artificial Intelligence for detection and attribution- Climate Change studies. Stay tuned!</description></item><item><title>ISP-IPL Growing Up</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/isp-ipl-growing-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/isp-ipl-growing-up/</guid><description>ISP-IPL growing-up New people and projects. Welcome! Exciting research and synergies going on! Check out our collaborators and projects sections -ERC USMILE, H2020 DeepCube, H2020 iMIRACLI, Deepcloud, Leaves, Maloc&amp;hellip; we explore the domians of land, atmosphere, ocean, computer vision and more!</description></item><item><title>Worldfloods Detection Model</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/worldfloods-detection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/worldfloods-detection/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Worldfloods&amp;rdquo; detection model onboard SpaceX’s Falcon rocket launched June 30th! Our script is now flying on a hard-disk at 20,000 km from the Earth! Successfully developed by ISP &amp;amp; Oxford University in partnership with ESA Φ-lab! Who made it possible? Gonzalo Mateo-Garcia, Joshua Veitch-Michaelis, Lewis Smith, Silviu Oprea, Guy Schumann, Yarin Gal, Atılım Güneş Baydin, and Dietmar Backes. Congrats!</description></item><item><title>AI for Sea Level Predictions</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/ai-oceans-sea-level/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/ai-oceans-sea-level/</guid><description>La inteligencia artificial llega a los océanos para desarrollar predicciones sobre el nivel del mar.</description></item><item><title>Highly Cited Researcher 2021</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/highly-cited-researcher-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2021/highly-cited-researcher-2021/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls was named a Highly Cited Researcher 2021 by Clarivate for Academia and Government WoS in recognition of his contribution to AI for the geosciences and scientific enthusiasm! We are all happy of being part of this great team at ISP, participating in inspiring research projects and promoting international collaboration networks, Gustau. Congrats!</description></item><item><title>Horizon 2020 EU iMIRACLI</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/horizon-2020-imiracli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/horizon-2020-imiracli/</guid><description>Starting on January 2020, - Horizon-H2020 EU iMIRACLI Bringing together leading climate and machine learning experts across Europe to train a new next generation of climate data scientists.</description></item><item><title>IEEE Distinguished Lecturer</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/ieee-distinguished-lecturer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/ieee-distinguished-lecturer/</guid><description>Prof. Gustau Camps-Valls was appointed as IEEE Distinguished Lecturer of the Geoscience and Remote Sensing Society (GRSS).</description></item><item><title>Interview in Nature</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/interview-in-nature/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/interview-in-nature/</guid><description>Prof. Gustau Camps-Valls was interviewed about the international research published in Nature, which provides a new vision in the quest to determine whether temperature or water availability is the most influential factor in determining the success of global, land-based carbon sinks.</description></item><item><title>Member of ELISE Network</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/elise-network-member/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/elise-network-member/</guid><description>ISP Member of the European Network of Artificial Intelligence Excellence Centres ELISE.</description></item><item><title>Mètode TV SEDAL</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/metode-tv-sedal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2020/metode-tv-sedal/</guid><description>Mètode TV SEDAL: From MètodeTV, the channel of the Universitat de València, SEDAL is introduced to the public.</description></item><item><title>Cool Toolboxes</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2019/cool-toolboxes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2019/cool-toolboxes/</guid><description>Cool! Impressive progress in our toolboxes - Gaussian processes repository &amp;amp; many more. Give it a try! Feedback welcome.</description></item><item><title>Jesús Malo Full Professorship</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/jesus-malo-professorship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/jesus-malo-professorship/</guid><description>Jesús Malo got the full professorship in Vision Science at the Department of Physics in July 2018.</description></item><item><title>Group Growing</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/group-growing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/group-growing/</guid><description>The group is growing quite a lot! New people with lots of ideas, background and expertises. Welcome Jose Enrique, Jose Juan, Diego, Dan, Emiliano, and Emma! Check their profiles and exciting research here!</description></item><item><title>H-index 60</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/h-index-60/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/h-index-60/</guid><description>We reached an h-index of 60. Follow our research here!</description></item><item><title>IEEE Fellow</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/ieee-fellow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2018/ieee-fellow/</guid><description>Professor Camps-Valls was elevated to the grade of IEEE Fellow by the Geoscience and Remote Sensing Society, and also recognized by the Signal Processing Society.</description></item><item><title>Jesús Malo Associate Editor</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/jesus-malo-editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/jesus-malo-editor/</guid><description>Prof. Jesús Malo has been appointed as Associate Editor of Frontiers in Neuroscience (IF = 3.4), section Perception Science (May 2017).</description></item><item><title>Composite Kernels Classic Paper</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/composite-kernels/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/composite-kernels/</guid><description>We are a classic! &amp;ldquo;Composite kernels for hyperspectral image classification&amp;rdquo; published in IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters in 2006 is one of the highly-cited papers in its area of research, maintaining its impact long after publication.</description></item><item><title>DSP with Kernel Methods Book</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/dsp-kernel-methods/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/dsp-kernel-methods/</guid><description>We are excited about the publication of our new book, entitled &amp;ldquo;Digital Signal Processing with Kernel Methods&amp;rdquo;, by Rojo-Álvarez, J.L. and Martínez-Ramón, M. and Muñoz-Marí, J. and Camps-Valls, G., published by Wiley and sons.</description></item><item><title>Geoscience Committee</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/geoscience-committee/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/geoscience-committee/</guid><description>Maria Piles (president) and Gustau Camps-Valls (member) in the Executive Committee of the Spain Geoscience and Remote Sensing Chapter. Let&amp;rsquo;s do things to promote technology and science in remote sensing!</description></item><item><title>Global Carbon Sinks Research</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/global-carbon-sinks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/global-carbon-sinks/</guid><description>An international research involving the Universitat de València just provided a new vision in the quest to determine whether temperature or water availability is the most influential factor in determining the success of global, land-based carbon sinks. The results are published in Nature with Gustau Camps-Valls as co-author.</description></item><item><title>Mètode TV SEDAL</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/metode-tv-sedal-2017/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2017/metode-tv-sedal-2017/</guid><description>Mètode TV SEDAL: From MètodeTV, the channel of the Universitat de València, SEDAL is introduced to the public.</description></item><item><title>Analog Devices 2016</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/analog-devices-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/analog-devices-2016/</guid><description>Analog Devices moves to the Science Park of the UV. New facilities and closer collaborations. Welcome back, Javi!</description></item><item><title>Analog Devices Moves</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/analog-devices-moves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/analog-devices-moves/</guid><description>Analog Devices moves to the Science Park of the UV. New facilities and closer collaborations!</description></item><item><title>Dagstuhl Seminar 2016</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/dagstuhl-seminar-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/dagstuhl-seminar-2016/</guid><description>Dagstuhl seminar on &amp;ldquo;Computer Science meets Ecology&amp;rdquo; gathering the best researchers of both worlds in a unique environment for fruitful discussions.</description></item><item><title>Dagstuhl Seminar 2016</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/dagstuhl-seminar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/dagstuhl-seminar/</guid><description>We organized a Dagstuhl seminar on &amp;ldquo;Computer Science meets Ecology&amp;rdquo; gathering the best researchers of both worlds in a unique environment for fruitful discussions.</description></item><item><title>ERC Consolidator Grant</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/erc-consolidator-grant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/erc-consolidator-grant/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls recently got an ERC consolidator grant (ERC-CoG) with the project &amp;ldquo;Statistical Learning for Remote Sensing Data Analysis&amp;rdquo; (SEDAL) for the period 2015-2020.</description></item><item><title>Google Award 2015</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/google-award-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/google-award-2015/</guid><description>Luis Gómez-Chova received a Google Earth Engine Research Award 2015 to foster research in cloud detection.</description></item><item><title>Google Earth Engine Award</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/google-earth-engine-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/google-earth-engine-award/</guid><description>Luis Gómez-Chova received a Google Earth Engine Research Award 2015 to foster research in cloud detection.</description></item><item><title>GRSM Special Issue</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/grsm-special-issue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/grsm-special-issue/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls co-edits a Special Issue on the IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Magazine (GRSM).</description></item><item><title>Hyperspectral Imaging Special Issue</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/hyperspectral-imaging/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/hyperspectral-imaging/</guid><description>Gustau Camps-Valls co-edits a Special Issue titled &amp;lsquo;Hyperspectral Imaging and Image Processing&amp;rsquo; for the journal Sensing and Imaging (Springer).</description></item><item><title>IEEE Distinguished Lecturer 2016</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/ieee-lecturer-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/ieee-lecturer-2016/</guid><description>Prof. Gustau Camps-Valls was appointed as IEEE Distinguished Lecturer of the Geoscience and Remote Sensing Society (GRSS).</description></item><item><title>IEEE GRSS Data Fusion Contest</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/data-fusion-contest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/data-fusion-contest/</guid><description>We won the 2015 IEEE GRSS Data Fusion Contest with a paper on the statistical analysis of the optical and LiDAR complementary information.</description></item><item><title>IGARSS 2018 Organization</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/igarss-2018-organization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/igarss-2018-organization/</guid><description>We organized here in València the biggest IEEE remote sensing and geoscience conference, IGARSS, in 2018.</description></item><item><title>Jesús Malo Academic Editor</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/academic-editor-plos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/academic-editor-plos/</guid><description>Jesús Malo has been appointed as Academic Editor at PLoS ONE for the period 2014-2017.</description></item><item><title>Learning Material Publication</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/learning-material/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/learning-material/</guid><description>We published learning material on geoscience and remote sensing data processing in IEEE GRSS training material and many more online available!</description></item><item><title>Maria Piles Ramón y Cajal Fellowship</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/maria-piles-fellowship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/news/2016/maria-piles-fellowship/</guid><description>Dr. Maria Piles joins the ISP group through a prestigious &amp;ldquo;Ramón y Cajal&amp;rdquo; fellowship next January 2017. The ISP consolidates the research line of retrieval of soil moisture and vegetation biogeophysical parameters from space observations (microwave radiometers, radars and hyperspectral imagers). Welcome Maria!</description></item></channel></rss>