<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SEDAL Grant on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/</link><description>Recent content in SEDAL Grant on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Methodology</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/project_structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/project_structure/</guid><description>Activities are organized in three major tasks: two theoretical tasks guided by an application-oriented one dealing with relevant EO problems.
Workpackage 1: Improving Statistical Regression Models We will develop new kernel regression models to cope with the shortcomings identified before, namely: improve model’s accuracy by encoding prior knowledge, quantify the uncertainty of the estimations, attain self-explanatory models, and alleviate the computational cost. We will develop ways to encode prior knowledge about the problem by design of kernels and neural structures able to:</description></item><item><title>SEDAL Project</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/proporsal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/proporsal/</guid><description>Proposals B1 Proposal B2 Proposal Interview Slides Reporting Continuous Reporting: 01/09/2015 - 28/02/2017 Mid-term Report: 01/09/2015 - 28/02/2018 Outreach Presentations Advanced Applications in AI (AAA) Algorithms and Analysis (AAA) Applied Analytics for Agriculture (AAA) Atmospheric and Aerial Analysis (AAA) The SEDAL project is an interdisciplinary effort to develop novel statistical learning methods to analyze Earth Observation (EO) satellite data. The project focuses on improving prediction models, discovering knowledge and causal relations in EO data, and contributing to various remote sensing applications.</description></item><item><title>SEDAL: Statistical Learning for Earth Observation Data Analysis</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/main_objetives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/main_objetives/</guid><description>Objectives Improve prediction models by adaptation to Earth Observation data characteristics. We will rely on the framework of kernel learning, which has emerged as the most appropriate framework for remote sensing data analysis in the last decade. The new retrieval models will be adapted to the particular signal characteristics, such as unevenly sampled time series and missing data, non-Gaussianity, presence of heteroscedastic and non-stationary processes, and non-i.i.d. (spatial and temporal) relations.</description></item><item><title>SEDAL: Statistical Learning for Earth Observation Data Analysis</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/sedal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/github/news/2016/sedal-grant/sedal/</guid><description>SEDAL is a research project funded by the European Research Council (ERC) Consolidator Grant 2015-2020, and directed by Prof. Gustau Camps-Valls at the Universitat de València, Spain.
SEDAL is an interdisciplinary project that aims to develop novel statistical learning methods to analyze Earth Observation (EO) satellite data. In the last decade, learning models have helped to monitor land, oceans, and atmosphere through the analysis and estimation of climate and biophysical parameters.</description></item></channel></rss>