<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Our Courses on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/</link><description>Recent content in Our Courses on ISP - Image and Signal Processing group</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anna Jungbluth</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/anna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/anna/</guid><description>About Me Anna Jungbluth is a Research Fellow at the European Space Agency (ESA), where she works in the Climate Team on machine learning applications for Earth Observation. She holds a PhD in Physics from the University of Oxford, where she focused on improving the efficiency of solar panels through charge-transfer state research in organic solar cells. Her passion for machine learning and space research began in 2018 when she won the UK finals of the ESA-sponsored Act in Space Hackathon.</description></item><item><title>David Chaparro Danon</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/david/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/david/</guid><description>About Me David Chaparro Danon is a postdoctoral researcher at CREAF. He holds a degree in Biology from the UAB and master&amp;rsquo;s degrees in GIS and Remote Sensing (2012) and Terrestrial Ecology (2013) from UAB-CREAF. He completed his PhD at the Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC) from 2014 to 2018, focusing on the environmental applications of passive microwave sensors in the L-band, such as forest decay and wildfire risk assessment. During his PhD, he conducted a research stay at the Joint Research Centre of the European Commission.</description></item><item><title>Devis Tuia</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/devis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/devis/</guid><description>About Me My research focuses on machine learning, remote sensing, and spatial analysis applied to Earth observation.</description></item><item><title>Ioannis N. Athanasiadis</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/ioannis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/ioannis/</guid><description>About Me Ioannis N. Athanasiadis is a Professor and Chair of Artificial Intelligence at Wageningen University &amp;amp; Research (WUR) in the Netherlands. He leads the Artificial Intelligence (AIN) group, a newly established team at WUR that advances AI methods to address global challenges responsibly. The AIN group conducts use-inspired, applied research in collaboration with experts from the environmental, social, and life sciences. With extensive experience in machine learning for agricultural and environmental applications, Ioannis is also a co-founder and coordinator of the AgMIP Machine Learning team (AgML).</description></item><item><title>Maurizio Mencuccini</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/maurizio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/maurizio/</guid><description>About Me Maurizio Mencuccini is an ICREA Researcher in Plant and Ecosystem Ecology at CREAF. Previously, he was a Professor of Forest Science at The University of Edinburgh (UK) and is currently an Honorary Professor at the same university. He holds a PhD from The University of Edinburgh and completed a postdoctoral fellowship at Cornell University (NY, USA). Mencuccini has been a visiting professor at Cornell University (USA), the Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona (UAB), and a visiting scientist at CSIRO (Tasmania, Australia).</description></item><item><title>Michele Meroni</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/michele/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/michele/</guid><description>About Me Michele Meroni is a Remote Sensing Consultant at SEIDOR and a former Scientific Officer at the Joint Research Centre (JRC) of the European Commission. With over eight years of experience at JRC, Michele has contributed significantly to global agriculture and food security initiatives, particularly through the Copernicus4GEOGLAM project. His expertise includes remote sensing applications for crop type mapping, crop area estimation, and the development of map validation services to support the European Regulation on Deforestation-free Products (EUDR).</description></item><item><title>Pierre Gentine</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/pierre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/pierre/</guid><description>About Me Pierre Gentine is a Professor in the Department of Earth and Environmental Engineering and the Department of Earth and Environmental Sciences at Columbia University. He is also the director of the NSF Science and Technology Center &amp;ldquo;Learning the Earth with Artificial Intelligence and Physics&amp;rdquo; (LEAP) and the director of the Graduate Program in Earth and Environmental Engineering. His research focuses on the multiscale nature of the continental hydrologic and carbon cycle, utilizing observations (remote sensing and in situ), models, and machine learning techniques.</description></item><item><title>Rafael Prieto-Curiel</title><link>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/rafael/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://isp.uv.es/english/speaker/rafael/</guid><description>About Me Rafael Prieto-Curiel is a faculty member at the Complexity Science Hub (CSH) in Vienna, Austria. Since May 2022, he has been a postdoctoral research fellow at CSH, focusing on mobility, migration, urban dynamics, and the demographic analysis of African cities. Previously, he worked at the Mathematical Institute of the University of Oxford and the Centre for Advanced Spatial Analysis (CASA) at University College London (UCL) as part of the Peak Urban project.</description></item></channel></rss>